# Maryam Ashfaq

Software Developer

As an IT graduate with a passion for programming, I bring a unique blend of technical expertise and creativity to every project. With a keen eye for detail and a drive for innovation, I strive to develop cutting-edge solutions that push boundaries and exceed expectations.



- maryamashfaq1828@gmail.com
- Islamabad, Pakistan
- in linkedin.com/in/maryamashfaq5

- +92 324 5250505
- maryam037.github.io/MaryamPortfolio/
- github.com/maryam037

### **EDUCATION**

# Bachelor of Science in Information Technology

**Bahria University** 

02/2020 - 06/2024

# Bachelor of Science in Computer Software Engineering(Exchange semester)

Altinbas University, Istanbul, Turkey

09/2021 - 02/2022

## **FSc Pre-Engineering**

Army Public School and College, DHA 2, Islamabad

07/2017 - 04/2019

## **PROJECTS**

#### Final Year Project

 LitterGo - AI Powered Flutter Mobile Application For Detection And Management Of Litter Dumps using Computer Vision.

#### Recipe Recommendation System

 Employed content-based filtering through feature extraction and cosine similarity to rank and suggest recipes based on user preferences, GUI developed using the tkinter library in Python.

#### Android Videocalling App

 Created a video calling mobile app using agora.io's video SDK classes, implemented in Java. Offering reliable platform for high-quality video calls for real-time communication and seamless video streaming.

### Suicide Rate Prediction

 Analysis on WHO suicide statistics, followed by training model using Random Forest Classifier after feature selection. Achieving an accuracy of 0.73 in predicting suicide rates.

#### Clothing E-commerce Website

 Utilizing HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, ReactJs and JavaScript, developed a visually appealing and responsive e-commerce website for an online clothing store.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Frontend Developer Intern

Teresol Pvt. Ltd.

07/2022 - 09/2022

Islamahad

Rawalpindi

### Intern

Inter Services Public Relations, GHQ

06/2024 - 07/2024

## HTML CS

SKILLS

Flutter/Dart

Python

rontend

HTML, CSS, Javascript

ReactJs

1400633

Datahases

SQA

Git and GitHub

Adaptability

Problem Solvin

Testing

AI/ML

Computer Vision

**Data Analytics** 

Mobile Application development

Web Application development

## **TOOLS**

Azure DevOps

PowerBI

Microsoft SQL Server Management Studio

Browserstack

VS code

Android studio

Jupyter Notebook

# **CERTIFICATES**

Data Science in Python - DataCamp (2021)

## **LANGUAGES**

English

Urdu

Full Professional Proficiency

Full Professional Proficiency

Turkish

Elementary Proficiency